Guide to the Katharine Brownell Collier Papers, 1895-1977 (bulk 1904-1934)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES II. EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS
  - Vassar College
    - Examination Questions — Ethics, Classicism and Romanticism, Geology B, B French, 1908; (7 items) (Folder 2.70)
    - Schedule of Classes, 1904-1905, n.d.; (4 items) (Folder 2.71)
    - AAVC re: life membership, revision of by-laws, annuity payment, includes 1 annotated item, 1923-1942, n.d.; (8 items) (Folder 2.72)
    - Correspondence re: events, reunion, alumnae fund, 1908-1947, n.d.; (17 items) (Folder 2.73)
    - Vassar Club of New York events, annual report, etc., 1932-1933, n.d.; (12 items) (Folder 3.32)
    - Athletic Association of Vassar College — Election Ballots, 1905/1906; (1 item) (Folder 3.33)
    - Athletic Association of Vassar College — Field Day Programs, 1905, 1907-1908; (3 items) (Folder 3.34)
    - Athletic Association of Vassar College — Record of Physical Measurements, n.d.; (1 item) (Folder 3.35)
    - Christian Association of Vassar College — Annual Reports, 1905-1907; (TS, 97 p.) (Folder 3.36)
    - Christian Association of Vassar College — Bible Study/Mission Study, 1904-1908, n.d.; (8 items) (Folder 3.37)
    - Christian Association of Vassar College — By-laws annotated by KBC, n.d.; (2 items) (Folder 3.38)
    - Christian Association of Vassar College — Election Ballots, 1905, 1908; (3 items) (Folder 3.39)
    - Christian Association of Vassar College — Prayer Meeting Topics some annotated by KBC, 1904-1908; (21 items) (Folder 3.40)
    - Class of 1908 — Freshman Year, 1904/1905; (9 items) (Folder 3.41)
    - Class of 1908 — Sophomore Year sign "Grinding Sophomore,", 1905/1906; (1 item) (Folder 3.42)
    - Class of 1908 — Senior Year Mohonk, Senior Parlor, "The Gassarion,", 1907/1908; (3 items) (Folder 3.43)
    - Class of 1908 — Commencement programs, luncheon, etc., 10 June 1908; (10 items) (Folder 3.44)
    - Class of 1908 — Class Songs, n.d.; (MS, 6 p.) (Folder 3.45)
    - Class of 1908 — Class Songs, n.d.; (TS, 1 p., oversized) (Folder 8.1)
    - Class of 1908 — Class Songbook, n.d.; (TS with MS notes, 76 p.) (Folder 3.46)
    - College Settlement Association — Brochures, etc., n.d.; (TS, 4 p.) (Folder 3.47)
    - Correspondence from Faculty arranged alphabetically by last name, including Laura J. Wylie and Elizabeth Hazelton Haight, ca. 1904-1908; (13 items) (Folder 3.48)
    - Correspondence from students, 1906-1908, n.d.; (5 items) (Folder 3.49)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, ca. 1904-1908; (15 items) (Folder 3.50)
    - Philalatheis Membership, 1904; (1 items) (Folder 3.51)
    - Society of Grand-daughters of Vassar College —Membership, meeting notices, ca. 1904-1908; (7 items) (Folder 3.52)
    - Vassar College Students' Association — Election Ballots, 1905/1906; (1 item) (Folder 3.53)
    - Advertisements for Vassarion, 1905; (1 item) (Folder 3.54)
    - Advertisements for Vassarion, ca. 1904-1908; (2 items, oversized) (Folder 8.2)
    - Vassar College (Folder 4.78)
    - Vassar College, Miscellaneous (Folder 6.14)
    - Vassar College, Miscellaneous (Folder 6.15)
    - Vassar College, Miscellaneous (Folder 6.16)
    - Vassar College, Miscellaneous (Folder 6.17)
    - Vassar College, Vassar-Yale Affiliation (Folder 6.18)
    - Vassar College, Trustees Proposal to the Faculty (Folder 6.19)
    - Vassar College, Report of the Comprehensive Planning Committee (Folder 6.20)
    - Vassar College Alumnae/i Affairs- Publications (Folder 6.21)
  - Bay Shore High School
    - Correspondence from other faculty members, ca. 1911; (1 item) (Folder 3.55)
    - Program "First National Bank,", ca. 1908-1911; (1 item) (Folder 3.56)
  - Bushwick High School
    - Correspondence from Brooklyn Public Library re: books loaned to the school, 1918; (1 item) (Folder 3.57)
    - Correspondence from Brooklyn District Attorney re: chapter 158 of Education Laws of 1918 and its effect on a French teacher at Bushwick, (2 items) (Folder 3.58)
    - Correspondence from Departmental of Education re: denial of KBC's application for license as assistant teacher, 1911; (1 item) (Folder 3.59)
    - Correspondence from other faculty members, 1918-1930; (4 items) (Folder 3.60)
    - Correspondence from High School Teachers Association of New York City, 1930; (1 item) (Folder 3.61)
    - Correspondence from parents of students re: students' tardiness, 1913-1914; (2 item) (Folder 3.62)
    - Correspondence from students re: a reunion planned by KBC, 1913; (11 items) (Folder 3.63)
    - Correspondence from students re: illness of KBC, 1925; (1 item) (Folder 3.64)
    - Correspondence to students from KBC — open letter to first-year students; advice as grade advisor; info for parents (in 3 languages), 1923; (5 items) (Folder 3.65)
    - Election Poster "Miss Collier for Treasurer,", n.d.; (2 items, oversized) (Folder 8.3)
    - Evaluations of KBC, change in salary, 1913-1942; (4 items) (Folder 3.66)
    - Programs — Graduation exercises, Bushwick High School Dramatic Society, 1918-1927; (5 items) (Folder 3.67)
    - The 3N-4J News published weekly at Bushwick Annex in PS 75, 1916; (oversized) (Folder 8.3)
    - Bushwick Beacon yearbook, 1914; (TS, 159 p.) (Folder 3.68)
    - Bushwick Beacon, 1916; (TS, 108 p.) (Folder 3.69)
    - The High School Teachers Association Bulletin, 1934; (TS, 4 p., oversized) (Folder 8.3)
    - KBC's Students in LI: Teacher Reviews (Folder 6.11)
    - KBC's Students in LI: Miscellaneous (Folder 6.12)
  - Columbia University
    - see also folders 5.55-5.58
    - Syllabus(?) for a history course, some pages missing annotated by KBC, n.d.; (TS, 5 p.) (Folder 3.70)
    - General correspondence to KBC from Columbia University, 1917-1928; (7 items) (Folder 3.71)
    - General correspondence, 1929-1930; (4 items) (Folder 3.72)
    - General correspondence, 1934-1949; (6 items) (Folder 3.73)
    - Correspondence re: publishing KBC's book Cosmogenies of Our Fathers, 1934-1967; (4 items) (Folder 3.74)
    - Correspondence from Lynn Thorndike, KBC's faculty advisor, 1928-1931; (2 items) (Folder 3.75)
    - Correspondence from Lynn Thorndike, including a draft of KBC's reply, 1932; (14 items) (Folder 3.76)
    - Correspondence from Lynn Thorndike, 1933-1934; (6 items) (Folder 3.77)
    - Correspondence to Lynn Thorndike from KBC, 1928, n.d.; (2 items, 1 fragment) (Folder 3.78)
    - Programs — Columbia University Library, Commencement 1934, 1930-1934; (2 items) (Folder 3.79)
    - Columbia University (Folder 4.77)
  - Other Educational Institutions
    - Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences: Extension Courses, School of Pedagogy, 1930/1931; (2 items) (Folder 3.80)
    - College of the City of New York letter to KBC re: her thesis in Feminism, 1914; (1 item) (Folder 3.81)
    - Annual Report of the Penn Normal, Industrial, and Agricultural School, SC, 1906/1907; (TS, 48 p.) (Folder 3.82)
    - University of Vermont re: summer session credit for KBC, 1927; (2 items) (Folder 3.83)
- SERIES III. ORGANIZATIONS
  - Alden Kindred of America
    - Correspondence: from Edward Alden, Secretary, 1927; (5 items) (Folder 3.84)
    - Events: programs of events, 1931/1932; (TS, 4 p.) (Folder 3.85)
    - Genealogy: Tracing the name "Paybodie" or "Peabody,", n.d.; (TS, 2 p.) (Folder 3.86)
    - Genealogy: Tracing Alden family, n.d.; (TS, 12 p.) (Folder 3.87)
    - Membership: Election of KBC as an absentee member, 1939; (1 item) (Folder 3.88)
    - Newsletter: Alden Kindred Gossip, October 1931; (TS, 7 p.) (Folder 3.89)
    - Newsletter: Alden Kindred Gossip, May 1934; (TS, 6 p.) (Folder 3.90)
    - Newsletter: Alden Kindred Gossip, Summer 1934; (TS, 6 p.) (Folder 3.91)
    - Newsletter: Alden Kindred Gossip, November 1934; (TS, 4 p.) (Folder 3.92)
    - Newsletter: Alden Kindred Gossip, January 1939; (TS, 6 p.) (Folder 3.93)
    - Newsletter: Alden Kindred Gossip, April 1939; (TS, 5 p.) (Folder 3.94)
    - Newsletter: Alden Kindred Gossip, May 1939; (TS, 6 p.) (Folder 3.95)
  - American Red Cross
    - Correspondence: from Adrian Van Sinderen, Chairman of Brooklyn Chapter, 1920; (2 items) (Folder 3.96)
    - War Relief Materials includes sweater patterns and small Red Cross logo, ca. 1941-1945; (4 items) (Folder 3.97)
  - Anti-Saloon League
    - Correspondence: from Ernest Cherrington, Director of Education and Publicity, 1933; (1 item) (Folder 3.98)
    - Pamphlets and brochures: policy statements, (2 items) (Folder 3.99)
    - Pamphlets and brochures: "Prohibition Facts," "The Lady or the Serpent?", (3 items) (Folder 5.1)
    - Pamphlets and brochures: "It Takes Two To Make A Bootlegger," "If Not Prohibition, What?" by Carrie Chapman Catt, (3 items) (Folder 5.2)
    - Publications: The American Issue, 20 June 1931; (TS, 16 p.) (Folder 5.3)
    - Publications: The American Issue, 5 November 1932; (TS, 16 p.) (Folder 5.4)
    - Publications: Anti-Saloon League Yearbook, 1931; (TS, 220 p.) (Folder 5.5)
  - Blue Pencil Club
    - Correspondence: among club members re: club organization, meetings, and various written works, 1925-1944, n.d.; (12 items) (Folder 5.6)
    - Programs: banquet programs, 1929-1932; (2 items) (Folder 5.7)
    - Publications: memorial booklets for Hazel Pratt Adams and Alice Lovett Lewis, VC 1904, 1922, 1027; (TS, 48 p.) (Folder 5.8)
    - Publications: The Brooklynite, official organ of the BPC, 1917-1918; (TS, 12 p.) (Folder 5.9)
    - Publications: The Brooklynite, 1921; (TS, 6 p.) (Folder 5.10)
    - Publications: The Brooklynite, 1923; (TS, 16 p.) (Folder 5.11)
    - Publications: The Brooklynite, includes annotated issue, 1924; (TS, 16 p.) (Folder 5.12)
    - Publications: The Brooklynite, includes annotated issue and 17th anniversary issue, 1925; (TS, 20 p.) (Folder 5.13)
    - Publications: The Brooklynite, includes annotated issue, 1926; (TS, 16 p.) (Folder 5.14)
    - Publications: The Brooklynite, includes annotated issue, 1927; (TS, 20 p.) (Folder 5.15)
    - Publications: The Brooklynite, 1928; (TS, 12 p.) (Folder 5.16)
    - Publications: The Brooklynite, includes 21st anniversary issue, 1929; (TS, 20 p.) (Folder 5.17)
    - Publications: The Brooklynite, 1930; (TS, 8 p.) (Folder 5.18)
    - Publications: The Brooklynite, includes annotated issue, 1931-1932; (TS, 12 p.) (Folder 5.19)
    - Publications: The Brooklynite, includes 25th anniversary issue, 1933; (TS, 34 p.) (Folder 5.20)
    - Publications: The Brooklynite, 1935-1936; (TS, 16 p.) (Folder 5.21)
    - Publications: The Brooklynite, includes annotated issue, 1937-1939; (TS, 16 p.) (Folder 5.22)
    - Publications: The Brooklynite, includes annotated issue, 1940-1944; (TS, 12 p.) (Folder 5.23)
    - Publications: The Brooklynite, n.d.; (TS, 2 p., fragments) (Folder 5.24)
    - Blue Pencil Club (Folder 4.80)
  - Congregational Church and Related Organizations
    - Clinton Avenue (Brooklyn) Congregational Church: church bulletins, 1914-1932; (4 items) (Folder 5.25)
    - Clinton Avenue Congregational Church: booklet "My Church and Its National Work,", ca. 1927; (TS, 23 p.) (Folder 5.26)
    - Clinton Avenue Congregational Church: correspondence from pastors, 1925-1929; (2 items) (Folder 3.100)
    - Clinton Avenue Congregational Church: Business and Professional Women's Club, KBC, Chairman correspondence, programs, 1926-1928; (5 items) (Folder 3.101)
    - Clinton Avenue Congregational Church: Women's League for World Service, n.d.; (2 items) (Folder 3.102)
    - First Congregational Church Bay Shore, NY: programs, bulletins, 1910-1911; (6 items) (Folder 3.103)
    - Miscellaneous Churches First Congregational Church, Washington D.C.; First Presbyterian Church, Brooklyn; First Reformed Church: bulletins, (6 items) (Folder 3.104)
    - Religious Union for World Peace, 1938; (5 items) (Folder 5.27)
    - Congregational Church and Related Organizations (Folder 6.22)
    - Congregational Church and Related Organizations (Folder 6.23)
    - Congregational Church and Related Organizations (Folder 6.24)
  - Fatherless Children of France
    - Correspondence to KBC re: Alice Bourdon and Roger Vinçon, 1919-1921; (6 items) (Folder 3.105)
    - Receipts for sending money to France, 1921-1930; (14 items) (Folder 3.106)
    - Fatherless Children of France (Folder 4.81)
  - Green Mountain Club, Burlington (VT) Section
    - Program from annual meeting, 14 January 1948; (1 item) (Folder 3.107)
  - League of Nations Non-Partisan Association
    - Letter from George Wickersham, President, to KBC, 1928; (3 items) (Folder 3.108)
  - League of Women Voters
    - Events, 1930; (2 items) (Folder 3.109)
    - Publications: "Weekly News" New York LWV, 1930-1933; (TS, 6 p.) (Folder 5.28)
    - Publications: "Green Mountain Citizen," Vermont LWV including Dumbarton Oaks United Nations proposal information, 1945; (TS, 10 p.) (Folder 5.29)
    - Publications: "Let Freedom Ring,", 1945/1946; (TS, 11 p.) (Folder 5.30)
  - National Amateur Press
    - Dues and membership info, 1930; (1 item) (Folder 5.31)
  - National League of Women Voters
    - Publications: "The Working Women's Club, What It Is…;" "The Club-Worker,", 1906, n.d.; (TS, 31 p.) (Folder 5.32)
  - Phi Beta Kappa
    - Membership and dues, 1908; (4 items) (Folder 5.33)
    - Events, advertisements, 1930-1941; (4 items) (Folder 5.34)
  - Student Volunteer Movement
    - Correspondence from SVM leadership, including brochures, etc., 1907-1908; (10 items) (Folder 5.35)
    - Correspondence from SVM leadership, including brochures, etc., 1915-1917; (3 items) (Folder 5.36)
  - Williston (VT) Historical Society
    - Membership card, 1977; (1 item) (Folder 5.37)
    - Williston [VT] Historical Society (Folder 6.26)
  - Women's University Club
    - Membership card, ca. 1904-1908; (1 item) (Folder 5.38)
    - Women's University Club (Folder 4.79)
    - Women's University Club (Folder 6.25)
  - Young Women's Christian Association
    - Correspondence, 1906-1907; (3 items) (Folder 5.39)
    - Events and programs, 1906-1932; (24 items) (Folder 5.40)
    - Memoranda, 1908; (TS, 2 p.) (Folder 5.41)
    - Publications: State Executive Committee Report, 1905/1906; (TS, 33 p.) (Folder 5.42)
    - Publications: "Bible Study Courses" and "This Year's Books,", 1906; (TS, 17 p.) (Folder 5.43)
    - Publications: Annual Report of Territorial Committee of the National Board of YWCA, 1906/1907; (TS, 17 p.) (Folder 5.44)
- SERIES IV. NOTES AND NOTEBOOKS
  - Notes Written by Katharine Brownell Collier
    - "The Indian" school composition, 1895; (MS, 8 p. 2 drafts) (Folder 5.45)
    - List of girls in 2nd Prep. B "I like, passable, I dislike,", 1899; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 5.46)
    - "A Girl I Know" school composition, 13 December 1899; (MS, 3 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.47)
    - History, test or quiz, 15 November 1900; (MS, 2 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.48)
    - "The Italian Fruit Vendor" school composition, 21 February 1902; (MS, 2 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.49)
    - "A Little Journey" school composition, 27 April 1903; (MS, 5 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.50)
    - Paragraph beginning "Orpheus cuma Manibus timeretur…,", [ca. 1904-1908; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 5.51)
    - Sketch of turkey, 28 November 1907; (pen sketch, 1 p.) (Folder 5.52)
    - Notes and a draft of a letter by KBC to principal of Bay Shore High School, including annotations by Laura Collier, ca. 1908; (MS, 3 p.) (Folder 5.53)
    - Story beginning: "St. Peter stood guard at the golden gate…,", ca. 1910; (MS, 4 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.54)
    - European History [Columbia (?)], 28 July 1926; (MS, 5 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.55)
    - European History [Columbia (?)], 12 August 1926; (MS, 7 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.56)
    - Columbia University Department of History, Foreign Language – French, May-August 1927; (TS, 4 p., 4 drafts) (Folder 5.57)
    - Columbia University Department of History, Foreign Language – Latin, ca. 1927; (TS, 4 p., 3 drafts) (Folder 5.58)
    - List of Christmas cards received, 1930; (TS/MS, 2 p.) (Folder 5.59)
    - "Those were the days" poem, ca. 1937; (MS, 2 p., 1 draft, 1 fragment) (Folder 5.60)
    - "Oh That I Were a Bird" poem, 21 May 1938; (TS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.61)
    - "There's a housing shortage in my garden…" poem, ca. 1946; (MS, 1 p., 2 drafts) (Folder 5.62)
    - "American Nation series…" booklist, n.d.; (MS, 3 p.) (Folder 5.63)
    - "anstatt or statt…" German vocabulary list, n.d.; (MS, 8 p.) (Folder 5.64)
    - "Are you some god or mortal?" excerpts from the Odyssey (?) some in Greek, n.d.; (MS, 2 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.65)
    - "Beautiful eyes are those…" verses, n.d.; (MS, 9 p.) (Folder 5.66)
    - Canoeing Time short essay, n.d.; (TS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.67)
    - "Class-meeting after luncheon…" verses, n.d.; (MS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.68)
    - Classic Slang, n.d.; (MS, 2 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.69)
    - "Coming from NY by car…,", n.d.; (MS, 3 fragments) (Folder 5.70)
    - Echoes from Birdland, (TS, 2 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.71)
    - Famous Pairs, n.d.; (TS, 9 p., 2 drafts) (Folder 5.72)
    - Famous Pairs, n.d.; (TS/MS, 8 p., 1 draft, 2 fragments) (Folder 5.73)
    - Famous Pairs: answer key, n.d.; (MS/TS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.74)
    - "For Mary G…" verses relating to various friends, (MS, 9 p.) (Folder 5.75)
    - "The foregoing generations beheld God…" short essay, n.d.; (MS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.76)
    - "Half our knowledge…" list of quotes from various authors, n.d.; (MS, 25 p.) (Folder 5.77)
    - "Il y a plusieurs…" various notes in French, n.d.; (MS, 22 p.) (Folder 5.78)
    - "It's easy enough to be pleasant…" poem, n.d.; (MS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.79)
    - Lakeview 1887 list of KBC's summer destinations, n.d.; (MS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.80)
    - "The last traces of snow…,", n.d.; (MS, 4 p., 3 drafts) (Folder 5.81)
    - Latin, n.d.; (MS, 3 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.82)
    - "My first wears my second…" riddles and key, (MS/TS, 3 p.) (Folder 5.83)
    - "No one thinks of…" essay about minimum wage, n.d.; (MS, 1 p., 1 fragment) (Folder 5.84)
    - Old Sayings, n.d.; (TS, 8 p., 8 drafts) (Folder 5.85)
    - "Peter Heylyn…" notes regarding books, n.d.; (MS, 2 p.) (Folder 5.86)
    - "Power of Emperor…" notes and outline, (MS, 4 p.) (Folder 5.87)
    - Scene 2 excerpts from a play, n.d.; (TS, 12 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.88)
    - "She determined to change…" verses, n.d.; (MS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.89)
    - "The sun drops down…" poem, (MS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.90)
    - Thorns and Roses verses, (MS, 2 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.91)
    - Topics for Discussion, n.d.; (TS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.92)
    - "Until recent times…" essay about gold mining, n.d.; (MS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.93)
    - "When that April…" verses, possibly removed from notebook, n.d.; (MS, 13 p.) (Folder 5.94)
    - Women, n.d.; (TS with MS notes, 8 p., incomplete draft) (Folder 5.95)
    - "Marches sitting room." Play. (Folder 4.82)
    - Plays (Folder 4.83)
    - "The Septemvirate" (Folder 4.84)
    - Academic Papers (Folder 4.85)
    - Short Stories (Folder 4.86)
    - Short Stories (Folder 4.87)
    - Verse, 3 April 1935; (1 item, photocopy) (Folder 4.88)
    - Notebooks: Biology, ca. 1908 (Folder 4.89)
    - Notes by KBC: Biology, 9 August 1935; (1 item, photocopy) (Folder 4.90)
    - Notes by KBC, ca. 1976; (1 item) (Folder 3.113)
    - Famous Pairs (Folder 6.27)
    - Girl's Names (Folder 6.28)
    - Riddles (Folder 6.29)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 6.30)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 6.31)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 6.32)
  - Notes Written by Others
    - Sketch of turkey by R. Batas, 1907; (sketch, 1 p.) (Folder 5.96)
    - Notes from a meeting of the NYC Association of High School Teachers of English, 1913; (TS, 2 p.) (Folder 5.97)
    - "If I Were a Boy" and "A Christmas Spirit;" written by a pupil, 1932; (MS, 4 p., 2 drafts) (Folder 5.98)
    - Verses and quotations written by others, (MS, 4 p.) (Folder 5.99)
  - Notebooks Belonging to Katharine Brownell Collier
    - "Katharine Brownell Collier: PCI" school notebook from Packer, 1899; (MS, 24 p.) (Folder 3.110)
    - Spelling book from Packer, ca. 1900; (TS with MS notes, 178 p.) (Folder 3.111)
    - Daybook, 1901; (MS, 32 p.) (Folder 3.112)
    - History class notes, probably from VC, ca. 1904-1908; (MS, 136 p.) (Folder 4.1)
    - Account book, 1905-1908; (MS, 72 p.) (Folder 4.2)
    - Daybook, 1909; (MS, 16 p.) (Folder 4.3)
    - 3-ring notebook, ca. 1941; (MS, 109 p.) (Folder 4.4)
    - Daybook, 1971; (MS, 108 p.) (Folder 4.5)
    - Articles about KBC, Miscellaneous (Folder 4.6)
    - Articles about KBC, Miscellaneous (Folder 4.7)
    - Articles about KBC, Miscellaneous (Folder 4.8)
    - Articles about KBC, Miscellaneous (Folder 4.9)
    - Articles about KBC, Miscellaneous (Folder 4.10)
    - Articles about KBC, Miscellaneous (Folder 4.11)
    - "One of Vermont's Great Ladies" source: The Burlington Free Press, 2 March 1977; (2 items, oversized) (Folder 8.4)
    - Obituary for Katharine Collier source: The Burlington Free Press, 5 July 1977; (1 item, photocopy) (Folder 4.12)
    - Notebooks Belonging to KBC, Block Pads (Folder 6.33)
    - Notebooks Belonging to KBC, Block Pads (Folder 6.34)
    - Notebooks Belonging to KBC, Religious Convictions (Folder 6.35)
- SERIES V: PERIODICALS AND NEWSPAPER ARTICLES
  - Articles Collected by Katharine Brownell Collier
    - Articles about animals sources unknown, 1890, n.d.; (6 items) (Folder 4.13)
    - Articles about art, sources: The New York Times, unknown, n.d.; (3 items) (Folder 4.14)
    - Cartoons and jokes, sources unknown, (3 items) (Folder 4.15)
    - Miscellaneous articles, sources unknown, n.d.; (4 items) (Folder 4.16)
    - Articles about or of poetry and prose, sources: The Burlington Free Press, The New York Times, The [NY] Evening Sun, 1903-1962; (3 items) (Folder 4.17)
    - Article about or of poetry and prose, (1 item, oversized) (Folder 8.4)
    - Article about or of poetry and prose, sources unknown, (12 items) (Folder 4.18)
    - Articles about politics: WWI, sources: The New York Times, the Chicago Tribune, unknown, 1914-1918; (18 items) (Folder 4.19)
    - Articles about politics, sources unknown, 1932, n.d.; (5 items) (Folder 4.20)
    - Articles about Vassar College, sources: The New York Times, unknown, 1905, n.d.; (2 items) (Folder 4.21)
    - Articles about philosophical and religious matters (Folder 4.22)
    - International Conciliation, 1912 (Folder 4.23)
    - Hints, 1915 (Folder 4.24)
    - The Family, 1927 (Folder 4.25)
    - Journal of the AAUW, 1945 (Folder 4.26)
    - Leisure Hours, 1929 (Folder 4.27)
    - The Social Hygiene Bulletin, 1920 (Folder 4.28)
    - The Meliorist, 1929-1930 (Folder 4.29)
    - Articles Collected by KBC (Folder 3.114)
    - Periodicals Collected by KBC, Vassar (Folder 6.36)
    - Articles Collected by KBC (Folder 6.37)
    - Articles Collected by KBC. "To the Women Students of America" (Folder 6.38)
- SERIES VI. PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Katharine Brownell Collier, Family, and Friends
    - Snapshot of KBC in bathing costume, August 1906; (1 item) (Folder 4.30)
    - Senior portrait from Vassar College head and shoulders, wearing a white blouse, photographer: E.L. Wolven, 1908; (2 items) (Folder 4.31)
    - Snapshot of KBC, outside, wearing black dress coat and hat, ref. number 3.557, 1931; (1 item) (Folder 4.32)
    - Undated snapshots of KBC: next to a boat, seated on the steps of a building, canoeing, next to a tree, including ref. numbers 6.557 and 6.558, (8 items) (Folder 4.33)
    - KBC with Packer class of 1906, 5th from right, middle row, January 1903; (1 item, oversized) (Folder 7.1)
    - KBC with other Bay Shore teachers, ca. 1908-1911; (2 items) (Folder 4.34)
    - KBC with class groups, Bay Shore High School (?), ca. 1908-1911; (2 items) (Folder 4.35)
    - KBC with class groups, Bushwick High School, ca. 1911-1942; (3 items, oversized) (Folder 7.1)
    - KBC with 6 unidentified women, standing on steps of a building, holding trays, (1 item) (Folder 4.36)